Guide to the Paula Vogel Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Paula Vogel papers
1949-2013
YCAL MSS 972
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
43.92
(43 boxes) + 7 broadside, 2 art
Vogel, Paula, 1951-
Paula Vogel
Paula Vogel (b. 1951) is an American playwright, university professor, and advocate for gay and lesbian rights. She won the 1998 Pulitzer Prize for Drama for her play How I Learned to Drive.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Box 38 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 37, 39, 40, 51, 52 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Digital files (student records): Restricted until 2095. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Digital files (financial records): Restricted until 2065. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Paula Vogel on the Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection Fund, 2014.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, photographs, family papers, clippings, audiovisual materials, artwork, computers, awards, and other papers documenting the life and work of Paula Vogel.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series: I. Writings, 1970-2009. II. Correspondence and personal papers, 1949-2013. III. Teaching materials, 1970-2009. IV. Photographs and slides, circa 1970s-2013. V. Posters, 1970-2009. VI. Awards and recognitions, 1990-2009. VII. Audiovisual materials, circa 1990s. VIII. Electronic media, circa 2000s.
American literature -- 20th Century; American literature -- 21st century; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Dramatists, American -- 21st century -- Archives; Women authors; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century; Dramatists, American -- 21st century; LGBTQ resource; Vogel, Paula, 1951- -- Archives
- Writings, 1970-2009; Series I; 17.08; (17 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Writings are arranged in roughly the order in which they were received.
  Scope and Contents
  Writings include scripts, drafts, production materials, research materials, clippings, and other papers related to plays and screenplays written by Paula Vogel. Notable works include Hot and Throbbing, How I Learned to Drive, Civil War Christmas, and The Mineola Twins.
  - Early plays, 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
    Titles; Balls, Cried the Queen; Meg; Dorr; Silver Threads; The Swann Song of Sir Henry; Apple Brown Betty; And Baby Makes Seven; and others.
  - Plays, 1980s-2004 (Box 2)
    Titles; The Oldest Profession; I Am No Angel.
  - Plays, 1990s (Box 3)
    Titles; Golden Girls - Hold the Mayo; The Unmasking of O; The Oldest Profession; Teaser; and others.
  - Hot and Throbbing, circa 1993-2003 (Box 4)
  - How I Learned to Drive, circa 1997-2000 (Box 5)
  - Civil War Christmas research material, circa 1990s (Box 6)
  - Civil War Christmas, circa 1997-2007 (Box 7)
  - Civil War Christmas research material, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 8)
  - The Oldest Profession, Hot and Throbbing, The Baltimore Waltz, How I Learned to Drive, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 9)
  - The Mineola Twins, circa 1990s (Box 10)
  - The Mineola Twins, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 11)
  - The Long Christmas Ride Home, circa 2002-2003 (Box 12)
  - Signature Theater and Arena Stage productions, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 13)
    Scripts, playbills, programs, and press.
  - Production materials from various theatres, 1970s-2000s (Box 14)
    Playbills, programs, press, contact sheets.
  - Clippings, photographs and production materials from various productions, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 15)
  - Clippings from various productions, circa 1980 to 2000s (Box 16)
  - Screenplays and Television Scripts, circa 1990s-2000s; 16; 16 Boxes (Box 17)
- Correspondence and personal papers, 1949-2013; Series II; 3.25; (3 boxes)
  - Family papers, 1949-2012 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, 1980-2013 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, notes and, contracts, 1996-2013; 3; 3 Boxes (Box 20)
- Teaching materials, 1970-2009; Series III; 9.75; (9 boxes)
  - Teaching files, circa 1970s- 2000s; 9; 9 Boxes (Box 21)
    Resumes, student evaluations and other materials.
  - Writings and syllabi, 1970s-2000s (Box 22)
  - Student writings, 2000s-2010s (Box 23)
  - Scripts used in teaching, circa 1990s-2010s (Box 24)
  - Student writings, 2000s (Box 25)
  - Student writings, 2000s (Box 26)
  - Student writings, 2000s-2010s (Box 27)
  - Student writings, 2000s-2010s (Box 28)
  - Student writings, 2000s-2010s (Box 29)
- Photographs and slides, circa 1970s-2013; Series IV; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Photographs and slides, circa 1970s-2013 (Box 30)
- Posters, 1970-2009; Series V; 5.83; (3 boxes) + 7 broadside
  - Photograph, Academy of Arts and Letters award ceremony (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - Present "On the occasion of her first Pulitzer Prize", 1998 (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - The Susan Smith Blackburn Prize, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - New York Drama Critics' Circle award for best play How I Learned to Drive, 1996-1997 (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - Hot 'n' Throbbing, Arena Stage, 1999 (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - How I Learned to Drive, Arena Stage, 1998 (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - Magazine pages from "Out", article Paula Vogel in High Gear., 1997 (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - Hot 'n' Throbbing, American Repertory Theatre, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - How I Learned to Drive, Intiman Theatre, undated (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - "The Mineola Twins", 1997 (Box 44 (Broadside))
  - "How I Learnded to Drive", 1997 (Folder 45 (Broadside))
  - Cartoon, larger version of "On the occation of her first Pulitzer" gift, undated (Box 46 (Broadside))
  - Kako Sam Naucila Voziti, undated (Box 47 (Broadside))
  - Najstarsza Profesja, undated (Box 48 (Broadside))
  - Como Aprendi, circa 1998 (Box 49 (Broadside))
  - Hot 'n' Thobbing, Graduation Performance N.C.U., 1997 (Box 50 (Broadside))
  - Posters and promotional photographs, 1990s-2000s (Box 41)
  - Posters, 1970s-2000s (Box 42 (Oversize))
- Awards and recognitions, 1990-2009; Series VI; 4.08; (6 boxes)
  - Awards and recognitions, circa 1990s (Box 31 (Oversize))
  - Award, 2003 (Box 33)
  - Awards and recognitions, 1990s-2010s (Box 32)
  - Awards and recognitions, 1990s-2000s (Box 34)
  - Awards and recognitions, 1990s-2010s (Box 35)
  - Awards and recognitions, 1990s-2010s (Box 36)
- Audiovisual materials, circa 1990s; Series VII; 1.08; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - 8 VHS cassettes, 1 Betacam cassette, 3 audiocassettes, circa 1990s (Box 38)